Also this morning, the City of Lexington is offering a new way to experience history with your family.
It's a new virtual reality experience and it transports you back into the days of the revolution.
City officials say that the high-tech help offers a unique way to keep the community's rich history alive.
Seven's Rob Way has the story this morning.
An otherworldly experience bridging Lexington's past with the present.
The iREV mixed reality tour taking place at the Lexington Visitor Center on Mass Ave.
the virtual experience bringing people all the way back to the 1770s to interact with the past
in a brand new way. We are so fortunate to be in a town with such consequential and fascinating
stories to tell. We always feel the responsibility of that history with the opportunity to tell it
in exciting and new ways. Previews of the iREV headset allowed users to explore buildings on
the Lexington Battle Green, as they were in 1775.
The very place where the opening shots
of the battles of Lexington and Concord
rang out on April 19th,
kicking off the Revolutionary War.
They are not a replacement for being there.
They enhance it by allowing history to step into spaces
they otherwise could not access.
The 20-minute tour, led by a guide in colonial dress,
takes users to models of either the Meeting House
or the Belfry, landmarks — buildings that were crucial
for the people of Lexington on the morning
the American Revolution began.
Grandparents putting on this headset with grandchildren.
We had people of all ages, different backgrounds.
Everybody understood that this is something new,
this is something different.
This is not another virtual reality project.
Travel and tourism experts say the experience
is not only a milestone for virtual reality,
but for Lexington's past and future.
This is an economic development tool.
people will come just for this experience and they will talk about it.
The moment you you put this on you are transported to another time and when
you're picking up things that existed hundreds of years ago it's it's an
experience that I welcome everyone to have and really enjoy. You can book an
iREV tour on the Lexington Visitors Center website. In the newsroom, Rob Way,
7News Today in New England.